International Workers Order Case Files 5940
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Workers Order Case Files
1950-1954
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
5940
12 cubic feet
12 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5736591
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 10, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Workers Order (IWO) was a Communist Party-affiliated insurance, mutual benefit and fraternal organization founded in 1930 and disbanded in 1954 as the result of legal action undertaken by the state of New York in 1951. Right after World War II, the IWO had almost 200,000 members.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5276: International Workers Order (IWO) Records 5940 mf: International Workers Order's Immigration and Naturalization Files on Microfilm
Socialism -- United States; Labor unions and communism; International Workers Order; United States. Department of Justice; United States. Immigration and Naturalization Service
5736591
- Kinoy files, part 1. (Box 1)
  - John Abb. Las Main File, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - IWO - Milgrom (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - IWO - Immigration and Naturalization, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - IWO Clinic, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fraternal Services Committee (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 80 Fifth Avenue Corp., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - JPFO - Convention Minutes (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Objections to Plan, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Plan, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - IWO - Papers or Legal Files (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dainoff Deportation, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - IWO - Stipulations, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - New York Central Committee - IWO (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bohlinger v. IWO - Supreme Court - Special, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Dmytryshyn (Counsel Fees) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Committee for Defense - JPFO, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Committee of 100, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Goldenberg vs. Camp Kinderland (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - People v. Dunn (CRC Bail Fund) (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - JPFO - Emma Lazarus Federation (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - IWO - Ridgefield County Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - IWO - Gross, Max v. Emdekay Realty, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - IWO - So. Bend Workers Home, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - IWO - Ohio Insurance, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - IWO - District 65 Negotiations, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - IWO - American Jewish Committee, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - IWO - Liquidation ( Legal Fees, etc.) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - IWO - Current Matters, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dmytryshyn (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - IWO - Deportations (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - IWO v. Bohlinger - Appel - Late Division, 1st Dept., 1951 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - IWO- Reinsurance - Documents (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Kinoy files, part 2. (Box 2)
  - Bohlinger - NYCP & Appeals - Extra Copies and Legal Papers (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Prehearing Correspondence, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - IWO Transcript Summary (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Insurance Matter - Excerpt from the Morning Freiheit, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents
    October 1950
  - Insurance Matter - News Releases from the International Workers Order Inc. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Insurance Matter - Office File Vol. 4 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Insurance Matter - Clippings Vol.1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Insurance matter files. (Box 3)
  - Insurance Matter - Important Paper File Vol. 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Insurance Matter - Important Paper File Vol. 3 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Insurance Matter - Clippings Vol. 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Insurance Matter - Office File Vol. 5 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Insurance Matter - Office File Vol. 5 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Insurance Matter - Office File - Vol. 6 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Insurance Matter - Office File Vol. 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Insurance Matter - Affidavits (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Insurance matter transcripts. (Box 4)
  - Insurance Matter - Transcript of Hearing before Referee Climenko Vol. 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Insurance Matter - Transcript of Hearing before Referee Climenko Vol. 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Insurance Matter - Biographical Data, Questions and Notes on Direct and Cross Examinations (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - IWO Matter - Digest of the Testimony of the Witnesses for the State in the IWO Matter, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    January 29,1951-March 7,1951
  - IWO Matter - Digest of the Testimony of the Witnesses for the State in the IWO Matter, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    January 29, 1951-March 7,1951
- IWO case and briefs, on appeal. (Box 5)
  - Bohlinger vs. International Workers Order, Inc. - Case on Appeal Volume IV (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Pages 2345-3106
  - Bohlinger vs. International Workers Order, Inc. - Case on Appeal Volume I (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Pages 1-770
  - Bohlinger vs. International Workers Order, Inc. Case on Appeal Volume III (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Pages 1549-2344
  - Bohlinger vs. International Workers Order, Inc. Case on Appeal Volume V (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Pages 3107-3830
  - Bohlinger vs. International Workers Order, Inc. Case on Appeal Volume II (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Pages 771-1548
  - Brief for Respondent-Appellant-Respondent International Workers Order, Inc., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Brief for Respondent, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Brief for Respondent (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Brief for Respondent and Intervenors (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Petition for Writ of Certiorari to the Court of Appeals of the State of New York (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Brief for the Petitioner (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brief in Support of Motion to Dismiss the Proceedings (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Joint Brief for Petitioner and Intervenors-Appellants (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Brief of Intervenors-Appellants-Respondents (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Brief for Respondent (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Brief of Intervenors-Appellants-Respondents (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Bohlinger vs. International Workers Order, Inc. Case on Appeal Volume VI (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Pages 3831-4195
- Bohlinger vs IWO case and other IWO files. (Box 6)
  - Bohlinger vs. IWO Volume 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Bohlinger vs. IWO Volume III, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Bohlinger vs. IWO Volume VI, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Pages 3831-4218
  - Bohlinger vs. IWO Volume II, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Contributions to the History of the Fraternal Movement Published by Two 1936 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - IWO Pamphlets (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cabinet#D 66 Ukrainian American Fraternal Union (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - IWO Cabinet #D-10 JPFO Translations, etc. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - JPFO Cabinet #G-22 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - IWO Croatian Society (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - IWO Loose Matters on Top of Files (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - IWO Jewish Peoples Fraternal Society Cabinet #D 8 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - IWO Jewish Peoples Fraternal Order Cabinet #D-9 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Douglass Lincoln Fraternal Society (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Polish (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Ukrainian American Fraternal Union Cabinet #D-67 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Spanish (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - American Russian Fraternal Society (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Jewish Young Fraternities (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Albert E. Kahn Files Cabinet #D-207 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Cabinet D-50 IWO (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Slovak Workers Society (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Garibaldi Society Translated from Italian IWO (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - IWO From Files of Sam Milgrom (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Serbian American Federation (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Carpatho Russian Society - IWO Inc. (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Assorted legal files, microfilmUS Department of Justice. (Box 7)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 1-147, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 213-322, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 323-368, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 369-474, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 475-620, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 734-818, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 819-943, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 819-943, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 944-1093, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 1094-1227, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 1228-1365, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 1366-1470, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 1471-1567, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 1568-1701, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 1702-1826, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn Pages 1827-1934, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Deportation Proceeding Against Andrew Dmytryshyn, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- IWO office files. (Box 8)
  - Ex. 24-100 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Herbert Brownwell Jr. vs. The International Workers Order Inc. - Office File (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Insurance Matter - Office File Vol. 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Insurance Matter - Office File - Vol. 7 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Ex. 154-171 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Cahill, Gordon, Zachry & Reindel Ex. 101-149 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Correspondence. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    from February 1951 thru: April 11,1951 Box #1577
  - Insurance Matter - Correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    May 16,1950-January 31,1951
  - Insurance Matter - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    from July 1951 thru November 30,1951
  - Insurance Matter - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    April 12, 1951-June 29,1951 Box #1577
  - Insurance Matter, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    January 1954
  - Insurance Matter - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    May 1953-December 1953
  - Insurance Matter - Memoranda (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Insurance Matter - Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    IWO Box #1577
  - IWO - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    December 1951-September, 1952
- IWO files, communist literature, reminders of Kinoy files. (Box 10)
  - Insurance Matter - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - State of New York Insurance Department - In the Matter of the Hearing on the Report on the International Workers Order, Inc. - Office File (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Insurance Matter - Respondents Exhibit to Hearing Before Deputy Superintendent (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Insurance Matter - Articles on "Translate for Bulletins" (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Herbert Brownwell, Jr. vs. The International Workers Order, Inc. - Office File (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Insurance Matter (Box 10, Folder 6)
    Releases by: International Workers Order, Jewish Peoples Fraternal Order, Douglas Lincoln Fraternal Society, Hungarian Brotherhood of the IWO, Ukrainian American Fraternal Union, The Garibaldi, The Slovak Workers Society, Hungarian - Russian Fraternal Soc
  - Insurance Matter - Exhibits (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Insurance Matter - Court Exhibits (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - H3 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- IWO files. (Box 11)
  - Brief for Respondent (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Brief for the Petitioner (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Reply Memorandum for Respondents, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Brief for Respondent (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Intervenors' Brief (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Insurance Matter - Memorandum Volume 2 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Insurance Matter - Office File Volume 1 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Bohlinger v. IWO (NY Supreme Court) (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - IWO v. McGrath - Supreme Court Case (Box 11, Folder 9)
- IWO legal files. Bohlinger file (4 bound volumes). (Box 12)
  - Bohlinger vs. IWO Volumes 1 and 2 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Pages 1-1548
  - Bohlinger v. IWO Briefs Appellate Division (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Brown v. Hugo Stinnes Corp. | Bohlinger vs. IWO (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Bohlinger v. IWO Briefs Court of Appeals (Box 12, Folder 4)